<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hacker-Blog</title>
    <description>A blog about engineering management from a non-engineering manager</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Talvalin</name>
      <email>someone@somewebsite.somedomain</email>
      <uri>https://talvalin.github.io</uri>
    </author>
    
      <item>
        <title>Start with Why</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;00-context-setting&quot;&gt;0.0 Context setting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s late evening on Saturday, 23 September, 2023 in Tokyo, Japan, and I am spending an inordinate amount of time fiddling with how I want this blog to look, instead of focusing on the actual content. This is not the most auspicious start to a regular blogging habit, but I am hoping that once I get past this hurdle I can just write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather is starting to finally cool down to the point where it is pleasant to stand outside in the evenings, compared to the humid heat of the long Japanese summer where it has stayed at around 30°C even at night. I am listening to Rush’s “Moving Pictures” on the recommendation of a friend, and wondering if I am the right frame of mind for this kind of music or if I should put some instrumental music on instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;10-introduction&quot;&gt;1.0 Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-not-writing-for-personal-development&quot;&gt;1.1 (Not) Writing for personal development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone who likes writing, I don’t seem to do very much of it outside of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to write book reviews for other websites, but lacked the discipline to finish those reviews, even when given a generous deadline. I then started writing reviews on my own blog but that fizzled out when taking notes as I was reading prevented me from enjoying the book. I also wrote reviews of metal albums on my very first blog, and later on annual round ups of my favourite albums of that year, but again I couldn’t maintain momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not writing niggles at me and it’s something that I want to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-so-whats-different-this-time&quot;&gt;1.2 So what’s different this time?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next month will mark my first anniversary at my current company. I am currently working as the Engineering Manager for a technical support team, and this is the third time in my professional life that I have managed a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many other managers, I have received no formal management training. In a similar way to how some people approach child raising by trying to avoid emulating their own parents, I have managed by trying to not be like some of the bad managers that I’ve had in the past. In my case this worked initially, but I ended up falling into other bad behaviours that those managers had not exhibited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late in my second stint as a manager, and more so over the past year, I have been trying to be more proactive about self-improvement by researching and reading about what &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; management looks like. I’ve still got a way to go, but I would like to think that I am better than I was a year ago and better than I was the last time I worked as a manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;13-thats-all-very-nice-but-why-write-a-blog&quot;&gt;1.3 That’s all very nice, but why write a blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to learn more about engineering management, I recently subscribed to the Pragmatic Engineer newsletter by Gergely Orosz. The archives are full of incredible content, but one particular post that stood out was the one about how to become a better writer&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-1&quot; class=&quot;fnref&quot; id=&quot;fnref-1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With remote work and distributed teams becoming more common, strong writing skills are a baseline for most engineering leadership positions. In fact, writing is becoming so important that companies like Amazon start their engineering manager screening process with a writing exercise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this article reminded me of a blog post I read by Jeff Atwood a long time ago about how writing his blog had been transformative&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-2&quot; class=&quot;fnref&quot; id=&quot;fnref-2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Atwood’s commitment to writing six blog posts a week was daunting, and yet somehow inspiring. Back when I was still a mediocre software engineer, I thought to write about my attempts to better myself, but unsurprisingly that didn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;14-do-better&quot;&gt;1.4 Do better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, finally, the point of this blog. In an attempt to retain the information that I have been taking in and to commit properly to becoming the best manager I can be, I am going to write about what I am learning and I am going to do it in public&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-3&quot; class=&quot;fnref&quot; id=&quot;fnref-3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is entirely for my own benefit, but if anyone else happens to read and learn from it, then even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s my first post on this blog. I am aiming to write one post a week and see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apologies to Dan Hon for stealing the format of his newsletter Things That Caught My Attention&lt;a href=&quot;#fn-4&quot; class=&quot;fnref&quot; id=&quot;fnref-4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great newsletter about the internet and life and you should read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn-1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsletter.pragmaticengineer.com/p/becoming-a-better-writer&quot;&gt;Becoming a Better Writer&lt;/a&gt;, January 19, 2022, Gergely Orosz &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn-2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/how-to-achieve-ultimate-blog-success-in-one-easy-step/&quot;&gt;How To Achieve Ultimate Blog Success In One Easy Step&lt;/a&gt;, October 27, 2007, Jeff Atwood &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-2&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn-4&quot;&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swyx.io/learn-in-public&quot;&gt;Learn in Public&lt;/a&gt;, June 19, 2018, Shawn (swyx) Wang &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-3&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn-4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsletter.danhon.com/&quot;&gt;Things That Caught My Attention&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref-4&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//start-with-why</link>
        <link href="http://localhost:4000/start-with-why"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/start-with-why</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
